Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh. Ugly
Naked Guy is decorating his tree.
못난이가 벌거벗고
트리를 장식하고 있어
Oh my God, you should see
the size of his Christmas Balls.
세상에, 저 남자의
크리스마스 구슬 크기 좀 봐!
Hey. / Hey. / Hey.
-얘들아!
-어서와
Hey, how much did you guys tip the super this year?
관리인한테 연말사례금을
얼마나 줬니?
Yeah, we were gonna give fifty, but if you
guys gave more, we don't wanna look bad.
50불을 생각하고 있는데
너희가 더 줬다면 우리도 더 낼게
Oh, actually this year we just
made him homemade cookies.
우린 쿠키를 만들어서 줬어
And twenty-five it is.
그럼 25불이다
You gave him cookies?
쿠키를 만들어 줬다구?
Money is so impersonal.
돈은 비인간적이잖아
쿠키가 다들 자기를 좋아한대
Cookies says someone really cares...
Alright, we're broke, but cookies do say that.
그래, 돈이 없었어!
하지만 쿠키 말도 맞아
I can see that. A plate of brownies
once told me a limerick.
이해해. 한 번은 초콜릿 케이크가
나한테 시를 들려주더라
Phoebs, let me ask you something,
were, were these, uh, funny brownies?
피비, 하나 물어보자
그게 웃기게 생긴 케이크였니?
Not especially.
꼭 그런건 아냐
But you know what, I think they had pot in them.
하지만 그 안에 마약이
들어있었던 것 같아
So you guys, who else did you tip with cookies?
또 누구한테
쿠키로 사례한 거야?
Uhh, the mailman, the super.
우체부, 관리인...
Oh, and the newspaper delivery guy.
신문배달 소년
Oh my God.
-세상에
-왜?
What?
Uhhh, I don't think you're gonna like this.
이거 보면 기분 나쁠걸
Ooh, goooosh, ooh, these are cookies
smashed in the sports section.
세상에! 쿠키가 스포츠란에
낑겨져 있네
Oh look, and he did my crossword puzzle.
내 낱말맞추기까지 풀었어!
Yeah, but not very well, unless 14-across, 'Gershwin
musical' actually is bitemebitemebitemebiteme.
실력이 별로네
세로 답이 '거슈원 뮤지컬'인데
'날 물어, 날 물어'라고 써놨어
I can't believe it's Christmas already.
벌써 크리스마스라니!
Ya know, I mean, one day your eatin'
turkey, the next thing ya know,
칠면조 먹은지가 엇그저께인데
your lords are a-leapin' and you geese are a-layin'.
벌써 예수가 부활하고
거위가 알을 낳았어
Which is why geese are so relaxed this time of year.
거위들이 요맘때 쉬는게
몸 푸는 거구나
Hey guys. / Hey.
-얘들아
-안녕
Hey Rach. I, uh, got you a little present.
안녕, 레이첼
선물이야
I'll open it.
내가 열어줄게
It's a Slinky!
'살금이'야, 기억나?
Remember, huh. Walks down stairs,
alone or in pairs, everyone knows it's...
'뭔가가 계단을 내려간다
누구나 알지, 그건 바로...'
just a big spring. Alright, you still
mad at me becuase of the whole...
'그냥 스프링이지 뭐'
나 때문에 화나 있는거 알아
그게 다...
Horrible and degrading list of
reasons not to be with me?
내 단점을 늘어놓은
그 저속한 리스트 때문이라구?
How 'bout from now on we just
call it the 'unfortunate incident'?
지금부터 그걸
'불행한 사건'이라고 부르자
Hey Gunther, you got stairs in your place?
건터, 집에 계단 있어?
Yeah.
Here, go nuts.
-있어
-이거 가져
Hey guys. / Hey.
-안녕!
-어서와
What's in the bag?
가방에 든게 뭐야?
Um, just some presents.
그냥 선물 몇가지야
C'mon show us what you bought...
뭘 샀는지 보여줘
너도 보여주고 싶잖아
You know you want to.
OK. OK, this is a picture frame from
Ben to my parents, huh. / Cute.
좋아
이건 벤이 할아버지께
드리는 사진틀
I got some, uh, hers and hers
towels for Susan and Carol.
귀엽다
수잔과 캐롤한테 보내는
여자용 타월 한쌍
And, uh, I got this blouse for mom.
이건 엄마한테 드리는
블라우스
Ross, that is gorgeous! / Yeah?
-정말 근사하다
-그래?
Look at these authentic fake medals.
이 진짜같은 가짜메달 좀 봐
I tell ya, mom's gonna be voted best dressed
at the make-believe military academy.
베스트 드레서상 받으려고
엄마가 군대 가시겠다고 하겠어
Hey.
-안녕
-어서와, 피비
Hey. Hi Phoebe.
Happy Christmas Eve Eve.
-해피 크리스마스 이브이브!
-너도
Oh my God, where did you get this?
이거 어디서 났니?
Uh, Macy's, third floor, home furnishings.
메이시스 백화점 3층
가정용품 코너에서
This is my father, this is a picture of my dad.
이건 우리 아버지야
아빠 사진이라구
Nah, Phoebs, that's the guy that comes in the frame.
피비, 그건 사진틀에
붙어 나오는 모델이야
No it isn't, this is my dad, alright, I'll show you.
아냐. 우리 아빠야!
이걸 보여주지
Phoebe, I thought your dad was in prison.
네 아버지는 감옥에 있댔잖아?
No, that's my stepdad.
그건 양아버지고 진짜 아빤 내가
태어나기도 전에 우릴 버리셨대
My real dad's the one that ran out on us before I was born.
How have you never been on Oprah?
왜 한 번도 부모 찾기 프로에
출연 안했어?
OK, look, see, this is him.
이것봐, 엄마가 돌아가시기 전에
이 사진을 줬어. 똑같잖아
My mother gave me this picture before she died, same guy.
Honey, uh, this is a picture of the frame guy
posing in front of a bright blue screen with a collie.
그건 저 사진틀 모델이 개와
파란 배경천 앞에서 찍은거야
It's not a blue screen... it's just,
maybe it was just really clear that day.
파란색 배경천 아냐
날이 굉장히 맑았나 봐
OK, I have to talk to my grandmother.
할머니한테 여쭤봐야겠어
Oh, wait a minute honey. / Phoebs.
-잠깐 기다려!
-피비!
Wow.
So anyway, I'm trying to get my
boss's ex-wife to sleep with me...
나 상사의 전부인을
꼬셔볼 생각이야
Joey!
조이!
Oh, but when Phoebe has a problem,
everyone's all ears!
피비가 말할땐
모두 주목하구선...
Esther Livingston.
에스터 리빙스턴,
사망!
Gone.
Hi, Phoe.
어서 와라. 아가야
Hi Gram. Whatcha doin'?
할머니, 뭐 하세요?
Oh, just updating the phonebook.
전화번호부를
정리하고 있다
Um, gram, um, can I see the pictures of my dad again?
할머니, 아버지 사진을
한 번 더 볼 수 있을까요?
Oh. Oh, sure, sure, uh, uh, how come?
그럼, 물론이지
뭐하게?
Just, you know, to see... um.
/ Oh, sure, yeah.
그냥 보고 싶어서요
그래라
This is the one of you father in a meadow,
여기 있다
네 아빠가 초원에 나갔을 때란다
and, uh, helping a little boy fly a kite,
이건 꼬마가 연 날리는 걸
도와주는 모습
and here he is at a graduation....
이건 졸업식때 사진
another graduation....
이것도 졸업식
another graduation.
OK, is this really my father?
제 아버지가 확실해요?
Is it really your fa--I can't... well of course it is.
진짜 네 아버지냐고?
물론이지
I smell smoke. Maybe that's 'cause
someone's pants are on fire.
누구 엉덩이에 불났나봐요
타는 냄새가 지독해요
Look, I...
Ya know, in all the years that we have been grandmother
and granddaughter, you have never lied to me.
할머니 할아버진 절 키우시면서
한 번도 거짓말 안 하셨잖아요?
Alright, that is not your father,
that's just a picture of a guy in a frame.
좋아, 이건 네 아버지가 아니다
그냥 사진틀에 있던 남자야
Oh God.
어쩜...
It was your mother's idea. Ya know,
이건 네 엄마 생각이었어
she didn't want you to know your real father
because it hurt her so much when he left,
아버지한테 받은 상처가 심해서
너만은 아버지를 모르길 바랬지
and, I didn't want to go along with it, but,
끝까지 숨길 생각은 아니었다
well then she died and, and it
was harder to argue with her.
이제 네 엄마도 죽었고
그 일로 입씨름하기도 어렵다
Not impossible, but harder.
물론 불가능한 건 아냐
Alright, so, what, he's not a famous tree surgeon?
그럼 아버지가
유명한 나무치료사 맞나요?
And then, I guess, OK, he doesn't live in
a hut in Burma where there's no phones?
전화도 없는 버마의 오지에
살고 있는것도 아니군요
Last I heard, he was a pharmacist somewhere upstate.
최근에 듣기로는
벽촌에서 약사를 한다더라
OK, that makes no sense. Why would
the villagers worship a pharmacist?
그건 말이 안돼요. 뭣 때문에
주민들이 약사를 숭배하겠어요?
Honey.
얘야...
Oh.
Anyway, that's all I know.
알았어요
그게 내가 아는 다란다
That, and this.
그리고 이거...
This is the real him.
이게 네 진짜 아버지다
Oh.
Ya know I remember my father,
아버진 빨간 양복을 쫙 빼입고
검정 부츠에 가죽벨트를 찼었어
all dressed up in the red suit, the big black boots,
and the patent leather belt,
sneakin around downstairs.
He didn't want anybody to see him
아래층을 살금살금 다니면서
남 눈에 안 띄길 바라셨지만
but he'd be drunk so he'd stumble, crash
into something and wake everybody up.
술만 취했다 하면 뭔가 깨부셔서
모두를 깨우곤 했지
Well, that doesn't sound like a very merry Christmas.
즐거운 크리스마스 같진 않구나
Who said anything about Christmas?
누가 크리스마스 얘기 했어?
Hi.
안녕
Hey, anyone hear from Phoebe yet?
-피비한테 아직 소식 없어?
-없어
No, nothin'.
I hope she's OK.
아무일 없어야 할 텐데
Yeah, I know exactly what she's goin' through.
난 피비가 어떻게 할건지
정확하게 알지
How do you know exactly what she's going through?
어떻게 안다는거야?
She told us.
우리한테 말했거든
So whaddya got there Monica?
모니카, 그게 뭐야?
Just some stuff for the party.
파티 준비하는거야
Yeah, what're you guys doin' here, aren't
you supposed to be Christmas shopping?
너희들 여기서 뭐해?
쇼핑하러 안 갈거야?
You guys haven't gotten your presents yet?
아직 선물도 안 샀단 말야?
내일이 이븐데 어쩌려고?
Tomorrow's Christmas Eve, what're ya gonna do?
Don't you have to be Claymation to say stuff like that?
누가 남매 아니랄까봐
저렇게 똑같이 말하냐
Oh, by the way Mon, I don't think
the mailman liked your cookies.
우체부는 네 쿠키가 싫었나봐
네 엄마가 보내신 장식품도 있어
Here are the ornaments your mom sent.
Well, maybe the mailman liked the cookies,
we just didn't give him enough.
쿠키의 양이 너무 작아서
불만이었는지도 모르지
Monica, pigeons learn faster that you.
비둘기도 너보단
눈치가 빠르겠다
Hey, Rach, you know what? I think,
I think I know what'll make you feel better.
레이첼, 네 기분이
나아질 방법이 있어
How 'bout you make a list about me.
나에 대한 리스트를
만들어 보는거야
Wha... forget it Ross, no, I am not gonna stand
here and make a list of... / C'mon Rachel.
말도 안돼
-어떻게 네 리스트를 만들어?
-괜찮아. 해봐
OK, you're whiney, you are, you're obsessive,
넌 징징대고 강박관념이 심하고
불안정하고 패기가 없어
you are insecure, you're, you're gutless,
you know, you don't ever,
you don't just sort of seize the day,
도대체 기회를 잡을 줄 몰라
you know. You like me for what,
a year, you didn't do anything about it.
나를 1년이라 좋아했다면서
아무것도 한게 없잖아. 그리고...
And, uh, oh, you wear too
much of that gel in your hair.
머리에 젤을 너무 많이 발라
See there, you uhh, alright, ya, you did what I said.
좋아. 내가 시킨대로 했네
Yeah, and you know what? You're right,
I do feel better, thank you Ross.
-이거 알아?
-뭐?
네 말이 맞아
기분이 좋아졌어. 고마워
Yeah, um, in Albany, can I have
the number of Frank Buffay...
네, 올버니에 사는 프랭크 부페씨
전화번호를 알 수 있을까요?
OK, um, in Ithica...
그럼 이티카는요?
alright, um, Saratoga...
사라토가? 오니온타?
Oneonta.
Alright, you know what, you shouldn't call youself information.
이것 보세요
절대 정보사라고 말하지 말아요
Hey.
얘야
Hello grandma, if that is in fact your real name.
어서오세요, 할머니
진짜 할머니가 맞긴 하다면요
C'mon now Phoe, don't still be mad at me.
너 여태 나한테 화났니?
How's it going?
어떻게 돼 가니?
Well, not so good. Upstate's pretty big,
he's pretty small, you do the math.
신통치 않아요. 나라는 넓은데
사람은 작잖아요. 계산해 보세요
Well, I think you're better off without him.
아버지는 그만 잊어버려라
Oh honey, I know he's your daddy but,
네 아버지인건 안다
but to me he's still the irresponsible creep who
knocked up your mom and stole her Gremlin.
하지만 네 엄마를 버리고 그램린까지
훔쳐간 무책임한 놈으로밖에 안 보여
No I just, just wanted to know who he was, ya know.
전 단지 그분이 누군가
알고 싶을 뿐이예요
이해한다
I know.
OK.
사실 너한테 솔직하지 못했다
나도 어디 사는진 몰랐거든
I wasn't completely honest with you when I told
you that, uh, I didn't know exactly where he lived.
Whattaya mean?
그게 무슨 말씀이세요?
He lives at 74 Laurel Drive in Middletown.
미들타운 74로렐가에 살고 있어
If you hit the Dairy Queen, you've gone too far.
You can take my cab.
데일리 퀸을 지나치면 안돼
내 택시를 써라
Wow. Thank you.
고마워요
Now, remember, nobody else drives that cab.
-절대 남한테 운전 맡기면 안돼
-그럼요
Uh-huh, got it. Ooh, I'm gonna see my dad.
드디어 아버지를 만나네요
고맙습니다
Wish me luck, Grandpa!
할아버지
행운을 빌어줘요!
Phoebe here with the cab yet?
피비의 택시는 아직 안 왔어?
Yeah, she, she brought the invisible cab... hop in.
왔어. 근데 투명 택시야
어서 올라타
Well she better get here soon, the outlet stores close at 7.
빨리 와야 할텐데
7시면 가게가 전부 문닫잖아
Hey, don't worry.
I figure it'll be 2 hours to Phoebe's dad's house,
they'll meet, they'll chat, they'll swap life stories,
걱정마. 2시간이면 끝나
상봉해서 떠들다가 인생사를
교환하고도 시간은 남아돈다구
we'll still have plenty of time.
Hey, here she comes. / Hey.
저기 온다!
Can you believe this. In, like, two hours
I'm gonna have a dad. Eeeshk.
믿겨지니? 두 시간 후면
아버지를 만나. 야호!
Eeeshk. / Yeah, big stuff.
-야호!
-의미가 크겠다
OK, let's go. / OK.
-그래, 가자!
-좋아
Alright, here, you have to hold this.
-이것 좀 잡고 있어
-알았어
Brake left, gas right?
브레이크는 왼쪽, 액셀은 오른쪽
Uh-huh, yeah, that's my cheat sheet.
그건 내 컨닝 페이퍼야
Where's my seat belt?
안전벨트는 어디 있니?
Oh, no no, that side doesn't have one,
the paramedics had to cut through it.
그쪽은 원래 없어
아마 간호사가 잘라냈을 거야
Hey! / Hey.
-친구!
-타!
C'mon, just tell me, please, please.
제발 말해봐
For the sixteenth time, no...
I do not think you're obsessive.
16번째로 말하겠는데 오빤
절대 강박관념이 심하지 않아
Oh, gosh, it's hot in here. / Rach, get the heat.
왜 이렇게 더운거야?
레이첼, 히터 꺼
오빠, 히터 좀 줄여줄래?
Ross, could you turn the heat down please? / Sure.
알았어. 근데 강박관념이란 건
의미상 구별을 해야해
By the way, there's a difference between being
obsessive and... / Ross, the heat!
-오빠, 히터!
-알았어
Fine, OK! Heat, heat, heat,
and I'm the obsessive one.
히터,히터,히터!
나보고 강박관념이 심하다고?
OK, this way is on, so this is...
이쪽은 켜는 거고
이쪽은...
off.
끄는 거야
Did you just break the radiator?
히터를 아예 부셔버린 거야?
No, no, I was turnin' the knob and, and... here it is.
아냐! 손잡이가 빠진것 뿐이야
여기 있어
Well put it back.
다시 꽂아놔!
It uhh, it won't go back.
들어가지가 않아
I'll call the super.
관리인을 부를게
Here, let me try.
이리줘. 내가 해볼게
Oh, oh that's right, I forgot about your ability to fuse metal.
맞아. 쇠까지 녹였던
네 능력을 잊고 있었어
Hey, it's Funny's cousin, Not Funny.
웃길 뻔 했는데
하나도 안웃겨
Hi, Mr. Treeger. Hi, it's Rachel Green from upstairs.
안녕하세요. 트리거 씨
위층의 레이첼인데요
Yes, somebody, uh, broke our knob on
the radiator and it's really hot in here.
누군가 우리집 히터 손잡이를
부숴놔서 지금 너무 더워요
Yes, it's, it's hot enough to bake cookies.
쿠키를 구울 정도라니까요
Well, do you think we could have a new one by 6?
6시까지 새 걸로
교체할 수 있을까요?
Wha t, no, no, Tuesday, we can't wait until
Tuesday, we're having a party tonight.
화요일까지 기다리라고요?
오늘밤에 파티가 있어요
OK, tip the man.
사례금을 줘
No, if he doesn't like our cookies, too bad,
I am not gonna be blackmailed.
안돼! 내 쿠키가 싫다면
그만이지 강탈당하긴 싫어
Look if worse comes to worse, it gets
a little warm, we'll call it a theme party.
최악의 경우 더 더워지면
특별파티를 여는 거지 뭐
Hey, here's a theme: Come on in, live like bacon.
주제가 뭔데?
'우리 베이컨이 돼 봅시다'야?
Ooh, this is it, 74.
바로 여기다
74번가!
Oh, so that's what this is for.
이 유리 용도가 이거였구나
Wow, this is it, I'm gonna meet my dad.
This is like the biggest thing ever, huh.
이제 아빠를 만나는거야
최고의 사건이지. 안그래?
Yeah. / Sure is.
-그래
-물론이지
OK, here I go. I'm goin' in. / Alright.
나 간다. 들어갈게
-잘해봐
-행운을 빌어. 피비
Good luck Phoebs.
OK, here I go...
좋아. 나 간다
here I go...
들어간다
I'm goin'.
간다
Hi, welcome to our tropical Christmas party.
열대 크리스마스 파티에
오신걸 환영합니다
You can put your coats and sweaters
and pants and shirts in the bedroom.
코트와 스웨터, 바지, 셔츠는
침실에다 벗어두세요
It's hard to tell because I'm sweating,
땀 때문에 구별이 어렵겠지만
난 젤에 써있는대로만 발랐어요
but I use exactly what the gel bottle says,
an amount about the size of a pea.
How, how can that be too much?
완두콩 만큼만 썼죠
그건 절대 많은게 아니예요
Ice, ice, ice squares anyone?
Take a napkin. Alright.
얼음사탕 필요하신 분?
냅킨을 사용하세요
네, 좋아요
Monica, Monica, your guest are turning into jerky, OK.
모니카?
네 친구들은 모두 벙어리가 됐어
Really? I'm perfectly comfortable.
난 만족스러운데
Hey, hey, hey, get in line buddy, I was next.
줄 서요! 내 차례란 말이예요
Mr. Treeger.
-트리거씨
-파티가 있다고 해서요
Uhh, you said there was a party.
Oh, yeah, well hey, welcome to our sauna.
사우나 탕에 잘 오셨어요
Ahh, is it hot? My body always stays cool,
probably 'cause I have so much skin.
이게 더운 건가요?
내 몸은 항상 차게 유지되죠
살이 많아서 그런가봐요
Hey, cheese!
치즈잖아!
Alright, alright, here's the chance. Monica give
him cash, Rachel give him your earrings.
좋아. 기회가 왔어
모니카, 현금을 좀 줘
레이첼, 귀걸이 얼른 떼어줘
아무거나 주란 말이야!
Something, now, anything.
No, I will not cave.
/ Yeah, I'm with Mon.
-난 양보 못해
-나도 모니카 편이야
Alright, alright, you know how you say I never seize the day?
그러면서 어떻게 나보고
기회를 못 잡는다고 말해?
Well, alright, even though he's your super,
너희 관리인을
이 몸이 잡아드리지
I'm seizing.
Mr. Treeger, here is 50 bucks, merry Christmas.
트리거씨
50불이예요. 메리 크리스마스
Oh wow, I didn't get you anything. Here's five back.
난 아무것도 준비 못했는데
5불은 돌려드리지
No no, no, that, that's your Christmas tip, alright.
크리스마스라 드리는
사례금이예요
Oh, hey, do you think there's a chance
you could fix that radiator now?
지금 저 히터를 고쳐줄
기회 아닌가요?
No can do, like I told the girl,
I can't get a new knob until Thursday.
이미 말했다시피 화요일까진
새 손잡이를 구할 수가 없어요
Ross. / Yeah.
-오빠?
-왜?
Looks like he's playin' baseball.
/ You mean hardball?
-야구를 하고 싶나봐
-하드볼 말하는거야?
Whatever.
뭐든지
What'cha gonna' do?
-어떻게 할건데?
-기다려, 내가 해결하겠어
Excuse me, I'm seizing.
Mr. Treeger, here's another 50, happy Hanukkah.
트리거씨
여기 50불이 또 있어요
해피 하누카!
Will uh, will this help with the knob getting?
이제 손잡이 건을
해결할 생각이 들죠?
No, the place is not open 'till Tuesday.
화요일까진 문을
열지 않는다니까요
Am I not saying it right.
내 발음이 이상합니까?
So, wait, you really did like my cookies?
제 쿠키 맛있었나요?
Oh, yeah, they were so personal,
really showed you cared.
아주 개인적인 질문이군요
당신의 정성을 엿볼 수 있었어요
Nice seizing... gel boy.
잘 잡았어!
젤 보이
So, uh, is this, uh, mistletoe?
이거 겨우살이예요?
Huh-huh, no act--no, uhh, that, that is basil.
아뇨. 해열제 약초예요
Ahh, if it was mistletoe, I was gonna kiss ya.
겨우살이면 당신한테
키스하려고 했는데
Huh-hoo, yeah, no, it's still basil.
아뇨
역시 약초예요
OK.
됐어
How far'd ya get?
/ Mailbox.
-어디까지 갔어?
-우체통까지
Alright, we're gettin' closer.
잘했어. 점점 가까워진다
Phoebs, what's goin' on?
피비, 왜 그래?
No, it's just like, ya know,
it's a whole mess of stuff, ya know.
다 뒤죽박죽이 돼버렸어
It's like, yesterday, ya know, my dad was this,
like, famous Burma tree surgeon guy and,
어제까지만 해도 아빠는
버마의 유명한 나무치료사였는데
ya know, now he's a, a pharmacist guy and...
이젠 약사가 돼 있다니...
Well, maybe he's, maybe he's
this really cool pharmacist guy.
-아마도 유명한 약사이실 거야
-그래, 아마도지
Yeah, maybe, yeah.
You know, and, and I'll knock on the door and,
and he'll hug me and I'll have a dad.
문을 열면 아빠가 날 반기겠지
나한테도 아빠가 생기는거야
Ya know and I'll, I'll go to his pharmacy and
everyone will be really nice to me 'cause, you know,
아빠 약국에 가면 다들 친절하게
대하겠지, 프랭크의 딸이라고
I'm Franks daughter.
Well, so why not go knock?
가서 문을 두드려
Well, 'cause, I mean, what if,
what if he's not this great dad guy?
만약 아빠가
위대한 사람이 아니면?
I mean, what if, what if he's just still the
dirtbag who ran out on my mom and us?
엄마와 나를 두고 내뺐던
불한당이면 어쩌지?
글쎄...
You know what? I've already lost a fake dad this week
난 이번주에 벌써
가짜 아빠를 잃었어
and I don't think I'm ready to lose a real one.
아직 진짜 아빠까지 잃을
각오는 안됐어
Phoebs, that's OK. You took a big step today.
피비, 힘내
오늘이 바로 결전의 날이야
Yeah?
Yeah, and someday when you're ready,
you'll make it past the hedges.
-그럴까?
-그래
훗날 네가 결심이 섰을땐
이미 늦어버릴 수가 있어
Yeah, and when you do, he'll be lucky to have you.
너만 용기를 내면
네 아버진 널 얻게 돼
You guys.
고마워
I'm sorry about your shopping.
쇼핑 못 가게 해서 미안해
Oh, that's OK, we'll figure something out.
괜찮아
다른걸 찾아보지 뭐
Uh, listen Phoebs,
I know you're not goin' in there but do you think
it'd be alright if I went in and used his bathroom?
피비, 네가 안 들어가겠다면
내가 가서 화장실 쓰면 안될까?
Oh, that's fine, never mind.
됐어. 신경쓰지마
Cool, snow, kinda like a blank canvas.
야! 눈이다
까만 캔버스 위의 눈이야
Ho, ho, ho, holy crap is it hot in here!
거,거,거룩한...거참
왜 이렇게 더워?
Really, hey, you mind if I turn the heat down?
내가 히터 줄일까?
Hey, we could have used that kind of thinkin' earlier.
우리도 진작에
그 생각을 할걸 그랬어
Hey, Phoebs, how'd it go.
피비, 어떻게 됐니?
Oh, I couldn't go in.
들어갈 수가 없었어
Honey, I'm sorry. / Are you OK?
-유감이다
-괜찮아?
Yeah, yeah, no it's OK 'cause, I mean,
I know he's there, so, that's enough for now.
괜찮아. 어쨌든 아버진 계시잖아
지금은 그걸로 만족해
Hey, guys, it's after midnight, merry Christmas everyone.
얘들아! 자정이 넘었다!
메리 크리스마스!
Hey, Monica, the knob was broken so I just
turned it off from underneath, I hope that's alright.
손잡이가 부러졌길래
밑을 잠궜어. 그럼 된 거지?
Rach, these are for you.
레이첼, 이건 네거야
Wiper blades. I don't even have a car.
자동차 와이퍼!
난 차도 없는데
No, but with this new car smell, you'll think you do.
이 차방향제 향을 맡으면
차에 탄 느낌이 들거야
OK, Phoebs, your turn.
피비, 이건 네거야
Ahh, toilet seat covers!
변기 깔개!
Is that what you were doing while I was getting gas?
내가 기름 넣는 동안에
준비한 거니?
You guuuyys.
-그래
-너희들!
And for Ross, Mr. Sweet-tooth.
이건 로스꺼
넌 단걸 좋아하잖아?
You got me a cola drink?
그래서 콜라를 주는거야?
And, a lemon lime.
거기다
레몬 라임도 있어!
Well this, this is too much, I feel like
I should get you another sweater.
이거 너무 많은데
난 스웨터를 한 장 더 사야겠어
And last but not least.
모니카,
마지막이지만 제일 나쁜건 아냐
They're ribbed for your pleasure.
특별히 갈비처럼
생긴 걸로 골랐어